字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
辣身舞
大家好，我是你们的朋友布鲁西
Hi, everybody. This is your cousin Brucie.
我们的夏日浪漫正值高潮，每个人都在热恋！
Our summer romances are in full bloom, and everybody's in love!
下面是四季组合演唱的一首很棒的歌
So cousins, here's a great song from the Four Seasons.
那是一九六三年的夏天…
That was the summer of 1963...
每个人都叫我“宝贝”，我却无动于衷
when everybody called me "Baby" and it didn't occur to me to mind.
那是在肯尼迪总统被刺杀之前…
That was before President Kennedy was shot...
在甲壳虫乐队到来之前…
before the Beatles came...
我迫不及待地要加入和平队…
when I couldn't wait to join the Peace Corps...
我觉得我永远找不到像我父亲一样了不起的男人
and I thought I'd never find a guy as great as my dad.
那年夏天我们去了凯勒曼山庄
That was the summer we went to Kellerman's.
西廊打乒乓球，东场打垒球
Ping-Pong in the west arcade, softball in the east diamond.
棒球手们都从那儿出去！
All you Sandy Koufaxes, get out there!
免费舞蹈课在凉亭那边
Complimentary dance lessons in the gazebo.
哦，天哪！看那儿！
Oh, my God. Look at that!
妈妈，我该把那双珊瑚色的鞋带来的，你说我已经带很多了
Mom, I should've brought the coral shoes. You said I was taking too much.
好吧，甜心，你应经带了十双
Well, sweetheart, you brought ten pairs.
但是珊瑚色的鞋才配那件衣服
But the coral shoes matched that dress.
这并不是悲剧
This is not a tragedy.
悲剧是三个人困在矿井里或者伯明翰使用警犬
A tragedy is three men trapped in a mine or police dogs used in Birmingham.
僧侣们自焚抗议
Monks burning themselves in protest.
别多嘴，宝贝
Butt out, Baby.
好了，十五分钟后在南边草地练习马术
Okay, we got horseshoes on the south lawn in 15 minutes!
我们的水上表演课在湖边进行
We've got splish-splash the water class down by the lake.
我们有静物写生课，排球和槌球
We have the still life art class. We got volleyball and croquet.
对于你们这些老家伙，我们还有麻袋！
And for you older folks, we got sacks!
医生！
Doc!
马克思！
Max!
医生，这么多年我总算把你请上山了
Doc, after all these years I finally got you up on my mountain.
血压怎么样？
How's the blood pressure?
我想让你们的女儿知道…
I want you girls to know...
如果不是这个人，我恐怕已经死了
if it were not for this man, I'd be standing here dead.
- 比利，拿包  - 马上，医生
- Billy, get the bags.  - Right away, Doc.
我留了最好的小屋给你和你漂亮的女儿
I kept the best cabin for you and your beautiful girls.
嘿，多谢
Hey, thanks a lot.
你想在这儿找工作吗？
You want a job here?
过几分钟凉亭里有梅伦格舞课程
There's a merengue class in the gazebo in the next few minutes.
最棒的老师，以前是个摇滚女歌手
The greatest teacher. Used to be a Rockette.
这是他六年来第一次真正的假期，马克思，放松
It's his first real vacation in six years, Max. Take it easy.
在这儿呆三周好比呆一年
Three weeks here, it'll feel like a year.
一、二、三、四！踩葡萄呀踩葡萄！
One, two, three, four! Stomp those grapes and stomp some more!
一、二、三、四！听音乐！
One, two, three, four! Listen to the music!
对不起
Sorry.
屁股动起来，尽情晃动吧！
Move your caboose and shake it loose!
一、二、三、四！开火车！
One, two, three, four! Start the train!
来吧，男士们！跟着我围成一个圈
Come on, men! Follow me into a round robin!
女士们，围成内圈！
Ladies, the inner circle!
来吧，女士们！
Come on, ladies!
上天赐予你们“响葫芦”就是让你们晃动它们！
God wouldn't have given you maracas if he didn't want you to shake them!
好了，女士们，现在我说“停”…
Okay now, ladies, when I say "stop"...
你们就会找到你的梦中情人
you're gonna find the man of your dreams.
停！
Stop!
记住，他是这儿的舞王，不过只是这儿
Remember, he's the boss on the dance floor, if nowhere else.
妈妈，爸爸，我上主屋去转转
Mom, Dad, I'm going up to the main house to look around.
这里有两种服务
There are two kinds of help here.
你们侍应生是大学生…
You waiters are all college guys...
我跑到哈佛和耶鲁把你们雇来
and I went to Harvard and Yale to hire you.
我为什么这么做呢？为什么？
And why did I do that? Why?
我本不该提醒你们，这里是家庭度假的地方
I shouldn't have to remind you. This is a family place.
也就是说你们的手指不要碰到水里，头发不要掉到汤里…
That means you keep your fingers out of the water, hair out of the soup...
并且要让那些女孩玩得开心
and show the goddamn daughters a good time.
所有的女孩
All the daughters.
甚至狗
Even the dogs.
带她们去天台看星星
Schlepp 'em out to the terrace, show 'em the stars.
- 想尽办法让她们感受浪漫  - 明白了吗，伙计们？
- Romance 'em any way you want.  - Got that, guys?
嘿！等等！等等！
Hey, hold it! Hold it.
好吧，这不是娱乐员工吗
Well, if it isn't the entertainment staff.
听着，自作聪明的家伙，你们也有你们的规矩
Listen, wise ass, you got your own rules.
陪女孩跳舞，教她们曼波…
Dance with the daughters. Teach 'em the mambo...
恰恰，只要她们付了钱
the cha-cha, anything they pay for.
仅此而已
That's it.
没有下文了
That's where it ends.
不许开玩笑，不许聊天，你的手也要放老实点！
No funny business, no conversations, and keep you hands off!
在哪儿都一样，有些人到林子里做爱，但也不许聊天
It's the same at all these places. Some ass in the woods, but no conversation.
当心，罗德里格兹
Watch it, Rodriguez.
约翰尼，你清楚你不能把手放在哪儿？
Can you keep that straight, Johnny? What you can't lay your hands on?
乖乖地把你的泡菜放在每个人的盘子里，大学男生，烈酒就留给我吧
Just put your pickle on everybody's plate, college boy, and leave the hard stuff to me.
请坐，我给你们来点酒
Sit down and I'll get you some wine.
谢谢，马克思
Thank you, Max.
这是豪斯曼医生和豪斯曼太太
This is Dr. And Mrs. Houseman.
宝贝，丽萨，这是你的侍应生罗比・古尔德
Baby, Lisa, this is your waiter, Robbie Gould.
耶鲁医学院
Yale medical school.
这些人可是我的特别来宾，他们要什么就给他们什么
These people are my special guests. Give them anything they want.
- 请慢用  - 谢谢，马克思
- Enjoy.  - Thanks, Max.
看看这些残羹剩饭，欧洲还有饥饿儿童吗？
Look at all this leftover food. Are there still starving children in Europe?
- 试试东南亚，妈妈  - 对
- Try Southeast Asia, Ma.  - Right.
罗比，宝贝想把她剩下的跞馑偷健
Robbie, Baby wants to send her leftover pot roast...
东南亚，所有吃不完的东西都打包吧
to Southeast Asia, so anything you don't finish, wrap up.
马克思，我们的宝贝要改变世界
Max, our Baby's gonna change the world.
- 大小姐，你你准备怎么做呢？ - 丽萨将装饰这个世界
- And what are you gonna do, Missy?  - Lisa's gonna decorate it.
她已经做到了
She already does.
医生，我想让你们见一个人，我的孙子，尼尔
Doc, I want you to meet someone. My grandson Neil.
在康奈尔大学学习酒店管理
Goes to the Cornell School of Hotel Management.
宝贝秋天要去曼荷莲女子学院上学
Baby's starting Mount Holyoke in the fall.
哦，真棒
Oh, great.
你打算读英文吗？
Are you going to major in English?
不，第三世界经济
No. Economics of underdeveloped countries.
- 我要加入和平队  - 最后一场演出之后…
- I'm going into the Peace Corps.  - After the final show...
我要和一些餐馆工去密西西比参加自由行运动
I'm going to Mississippi with a couple of busboys, freedom ride.
这位是我们的蒂托・苏亚雷斯
This is our own Tito Suarez.
曼波！耶！来吧！
Mambo! Yeah! Come on!
那是谁？
Who's that?
哦，他们是舞者
Oh, them. They're the dance people.
他们在这儿是让客人开心的
They're here to keep the guests happy.
他们不应该互相炫耀，这样人们会不去上课的
They shouldn't show off with each other. That's not gonna sell lessons.
- 嗨，孩子们，玩得好吗？ - 是的
- Hi, kids. Having fun?  - Yeah.
我得失陪一下，我负责今晚的游戏
Actually, I've gotta excuse myself. I'm in charge of the games tonight.
你愿意帮我开个头吗？
Would you like to help me get things started?
她当然愿意
Sure she would.
这只会让你疼一小会儿，你买过蓝十字保险了，对吧？
This'll only hurt for a minute. You've got Blue Cross, right?
感觉不错吧？
Was that good for you?
为了这么有趣的游戏，奖给你！
And for being such a good sport, here you go!
我终于遇到了跟我妈一模一样的女孩
I finally met a girl exactly like my mother.
穿得像她，动作像她，所以我把她带回家
Dresses like her, acts like her. So I brought her home.
我爸爸却不喜欢她！
My father doesn't like her!
想像一下吧
Go figure.
职工宿舍，客人勿进
- 嗨  - 你怎么到这儿来？
- Hi.  - How'd you get here?
- 我在散步  - 回去
- I was taking a walk.  - Go back.
我来帮你吧，那里在干什么？
Let me help you. What's up there?
客人勿进，这是规矩
No guests allowed. House rules.
你为什么不回表演厅呢？我看见你和小老板跳舞
Why don't you go back to the playhouse? I saw you dancing with little boss man.
你能别说出去吗？
Can you keep a secret?
你的父母会杀了你
Your parents would kill you.
马克思会杀了我
Max would kill me.
他们在哪儿学的？
Where'd they learn to do that?
哪儿？
Where?
不知道，孩子们回家后就在地下室里这么跳
I don't know. Kids are doing it in their basements back home.
想试试吗？
Wanna try it?
来吧，宝贝
Come on, Baby.
你能想像在专门跳狐步舞的主屋一楼…
Can you imagine dancing like this on the main floor...
跳这种舞吗？
home of the family fox-trot?
马克思非关门不可
Max would close the place down first.
那是我的表哥，约翰尼・卡斯尔
That's my cousin, Johnny Castle.
这份工作是他帮我找的
He got me the job here.
- 他们在一起看上去很般配  - 是的
- They look great together.  - Yeah.
你以为他们是情侣，是吗？
You'd think they were a couple, wouldn't you?
- 不是吗？ - 不，从我们小时候起就不是
- Aren't they?  - No, not since we were kids.
表弟，她在这儿干什么？
Yo, cousin, what's she doing here?
她跟我一起来的
She came with me. She's with me.
我抱来一个大西瓜
I carried a watermelon.
我抱来一个大西瓜？
I carried a watermelon?
膝盖弯曲，往下
Bend your knees. Down.
看，看着我的眼睛
Watch. Watch my eyes.
很好
Good.
好多了
That's better.
好，现在就这样摇动
Good. Now roll this way.
现在注意
Now watch.
看着
Look.
女士们，加入我们的惊悚假发秀吧
Ladies, join our hair-raising wig show.
试试桑德拉・狄，杰奎琳・肯尼迪…
Try your Sandra Dee, Jackie Kennedy...
或者伊丽莎白・泰勒的埃及艳后假发
or Elizabeth Taylor-Cleopatra wig.
- 我出三  - 真漂亮
- I'll knock with three.  - Look at that cute fella.
看看这双手，真是双金手
Look at these hands. They're golden hands.
天哪，埃及艳后！我觉得像条毒蛇
My God, it's Cleopatra! I feel like such an "asp".
你看起来年轻了十岁
You look ten years younger.
十点十五分，游泳池旁边会有健美操
At 10:15, by the pool, we have calisthenics.
然后拉比・毛里斯・舍尔曼将在西廊开展…
Then on the west porch, we have a symposium by Rabbi Maurice Sherman...
一场侮辱喜剧演员心理学的座谈会
on the psychology of insult comedians.
所以我说，不要问你的侍者能为你做什么
So I say, "Ask not what your waiter can do for you...
问问你能为你的侍者做什么
but what you can do for your waiter."
如果小费源源不断，我就能买辆爱快罗密欧了
If tips keep up, I'll have enough for my Alfa Romeo.
那是我最喜欢的车
That's my favorite car.
女士们，你们看起来很可爱
Ladies, you look very lovely.
宝贝，你今晚能不能帮我打掩护？就跟爸妈说我去休息了
Baby, would you cover for me tonight? Tell Mom and Dad I went to lie down.
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
高尔夫球场，从第一棵树可以看到很美的风景
To the golf course. There's a pretty view from the first tee.
很好，谢谢
Good. Thanks.
你以前真是个摇滚歌手？
So you were really a Rockette?
我觉得你的舞跳得好极了
I think you're a wonderful dancer.
是吗？我十六岁时我妈就把我踢出了家门
Yeah? Well, my mother kicked me out when I was 16.
从此我就开始跳舞，反正这是我唯一想做的事
I've been dancing ever since. It's the only thing I ever wanted to do anyway.
我很羡慕你
I envy you.
- 你不跳吗，医生？ - 我们在等华尔兹
- Aren't you dancing, Doc?  - We're waiting for a waltz.
马克思，我的舞蹈课开始有成效了吗？
Hi, Max. Aren't my dance lessons starting to pay off?
你棒极了，薇薇安！非常好
You look great, Vivian! Terrific!
那是薇薇安・普莱斯曼
That's Vivian Pressman, one of the bungalow bunnies.
她整周都呆在这里
That's what we call the women who stay here all week.
她丈夫只有周末才来
The husbands only come up on weekends.
莫尔・普莱斯曼是个打牌高手，他将会加入我们的游戏
Moe Pressman's a big card player. He'll join our game.
- 莫尔星期五来吗？ - 星期五
- Moe coming up on Friday?  - Friday.
他老是出门，我知道
He's away a lot. I know.
很痛苦
It's a hardship.
佩妮在哪儿？大家都在问她呢
Where's Penny? Everybody's been asking for her.
你什么意思？佩妮在哪儿？她在休息，她需要休息
What do you mean, where's Penny? She's taking a break. She needs a break.
只要不是整晚的休息
As long as it's not an all-night break.
来吧，宝贝，我们去散散步
Come on, doll. Let's take a walk.
我喜欢看你的秀发在风中轻扬的样子
I love to watch your hair blowing in the breeze.
也许我父母正在找我
Maybe my parents are looking for me.
宝贝，不用担心
Baby, don't worry.
如果他们知道你跟我一起，他们会是凯勒曼山庄最开心的家长
If they think you're with me, they'll be the happiest parents at Kellerman's.
我得说…
I have to say it.
- 大家都知道我是这里的继承人  - 我知道你是
- I'm known as the catch of the county.  - I'm sure you are.
上周我从救生员杰米那里抢走了一个女孩
Last week I took a girl away from Jamie, the lifeguard.
他对她说：“他有什么是我没有的？”
And he said to her, "What does he have that I don't have?"
她说：“两间酒店”
And she said, "Two hotels."
罗比
Robbie.
我没有听到一声道歉
I don't hear an apology.
回到妈妈爸爸那里去，也许你会在梦中听到的
Go back to Mommy and Daddy and listen. Maybe you'll hear one in your dreams.
很抱歉你总会看到这些，宝贝
I'm sorry you had to see that, Baby.
有时候在这个世界上…
Sometimes in this world...
你会看到你不想看到的东西
you see things you don't wanna see.
你饿了吗？
You hungry?
来吧
Come on.
宝贝，你想吃什么？你想吃什么有什么
So, Baby, what do you want? You can have anything you want.
果仁巧克力饼，牛奶…
A brownie, some milk...
剩下的米饭布丁，甜菜…
leftover rice pudding, beets...
甘蓝卷…
cabbage roll...
水果沙拉，甜黄瓜？
fruit salad, sweet gherkins?
尼尔，对不起，我得去看看丽萨
Neil, look, I'm sorry. I better go check on Lisa.
是的
Yeah.
- 她怎么在那儿？ - 万一尼尔回来怎么办？
- Why's she here?  - In case Neil comes back.
佩妮就是不考虑后果
Penny just doesn't think.
她不会做傻事吧？
She wouldn't do anything stupid, would she?
怎么回事？她怎么了？
So, what's wrong? What's the matter with her?
- 她怀孕了，宝贝  - 比利！
- She's knocked up, Baby.  - Billy!
- 他打算怎么做？ - “他打算怎么做？”
- What's he gonna do about it?  - "What's he gonna do about it?"
是我的孩子，是吗？
It's mine, right?
- 现在你认为是我的  - 但我以为…
- Right away you think it's mine.  - But I thought...
好了，约翰尼在这儿呢
It's okay. Johnny's here.
我不会让你出任何事情的
I'm never gonna let anything happen to you.
我们得走了
We got to go.
抓住我，抓住我
Just hold on. Just hold on.
好孩子，好孩子
Good girl. Good girl.
你知道你在做什么吗？你有麻烦就跟我说
What do you think you're doing? You're in trouble, you talk to me.
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
你应该首先来找我
You should've come to me in the first place.
算了吧，约翰尼，我不能拿你剩下的薪水
Forget it, Johnny. I'm not taking what's left of your salary.
- 佩妮，那也是我的事  - 并且那也不够用
- Penny, that's my business.  - Besides, it wouldn't be enough.
哦，天哪，完了
Oh, God, it's hopeless!
别这么说
Don't say that.
总会有解决办法的
There's gotta be a way to work it out.
宝贝？那是你的名字吗？
Baby? Is that your name?
你知道什么，宝贝？
You know what, Baby?
我的问题你知道个屁
You don't know shit about my problems.
我告诉她了
I told her.
天哪！她会告诉她的经理男友，我们都会被开除的
Jesus! She's gonna tell her management boyfriend and then we'll all get fired.
你干脆告诉所有人“佩妮怀了罗比的孩子”
Why not skywrite it? "Penny got knocked up by Robbie, the creep."
- 罗比？ - 不，宝贝
- Robbie?  - No, Baby.
有个顾问认识一位医生，一个真正的医学博士
One of the counselors knows a doctor, a real M. D...
他下周某天会来新帕尔兹
just traveling through New Paltz one day next week.
我们可以预约，但这得花两百五十美元
We can get an appointment, but it costs $250.
不过既然是罗比，应该没问题，我知道他有钱
But if it's Robbie, there's no problem. I know he has the money.
- 我敢肯定如果你告诉他…  - 他知道
- I'm sure if you tell him...  - He knows.
回你的婴儿床吧，宝贝
Go back to your playpen, Baby.
- 不需要你来告诉我什么是对的  - 你不能丢下她不管
- Why should you tell me what's right?  - You can't just leave her.
我可不想让一个暑假的努力因为一个女人而泡汤
I didn't blow a summer hauling bagels just to bail out some chick...
一个可能和这里每一个人上床的女人
who probably slept with every guy here.
更准确地说
A little precision, please.
有些人能上她而有些人不能
Some people count and some people don't.
读读这个
Read it.
我想你会喜欢的，但是得还我，我在里面做了笔记
I think you'll enjoy it. But return it. I have notes in there.
你让我觉得很恶心，离我远点
You make me sick. Stay away from me.
离我妹妹远点，否则我会让你被解雇的
Stay away from my sister or I'll have you fired.
我哪里不对了？
What am I doing wrong?
你打得太高了，玛姬
You're lining it up a little wrong, Marge.
如果你妈有一天离开了我，她肯定是去找阿诺德・帕尔默了
If your mother ever leaves me, it'll be for Arnold Palmer.
- 爸爸，有人遇到麻烦了  - 除了你妈还有别人？
- Daddy, someone's in trouble.  - Besides your mother?
你矫枉过正了，玛姬
You're overcorrecting, Marge.
你总是告诉我如果有人遇到麻烦，我应该帮忙
You always told me if someone was in trouble, I should help.
你能借我两百五十美元吗？
Could you lend me $250?
你没事吧？你遇到麻烦了吗？
Are you all right? Are you in trouble?
不，不是我，你能借我吗？
No, it's not me. Could you loan it to me?
这可不是一笔小钱，用来干什么？
That's a lot of money. What's it for?
宝贝，站直
Baby, stand up straight.
我不能告诉你
I can't tell you.
这么跟你说话让我很为难，但我不能告诉你
It's hard for me to say that to you, but I can't.
你总是说你什么都可以告诉我
You always said you could tell me anything.
这件事我不能告诉你
I can't tell you this.
不是违法的事情吧？
It's not illegal, is it?
不是，爸爸
No, Daddy.
这么问真愚蠢，原谅我
That was a stupid thing to ask. Forgive me.
我晚饭之前给你
I'll have it for you before dinner.
- 没出什么事吧？ - 没事
- Is everything all right?  - Fine.
谢谢，爸爸
Thanks, Daddy.
给你钱
Here's the money.
- 罗比给的？ - 不，你对他的判断是对的
- You mean Robbie?  - No. You were right about him.
- 那你从哪儿拿的？ - 你说你需要钱
- Then where'd you get it?  - You said you needed it.
- 这孩子是说真的吗？ - 找爸爸要钱救济他人
- Is this kid for real?  - Takes a real saint to ask Daddy.
谢谢，宝贝，但我不能用它
Thanks, Baby, but I can't use it.
什么？你怎么了？你应该收下的
What? What's the matter with you? You should take the money.
我只能帮她约在星期四
I can only get her an appointment for Thursday.
他们星期四在秋沙鸭有表演
They do their act at the Sheldrake Thursday.
如果他们取消，他们就拿不到这一季的工资，明年的演出机会也没了
If they cancel, they lose this season's salary and next year's gig.
秋沙鸭是什么？
What's the Sheldrake?
另一家酒店，他们在那儿跳曼波
It's another hotel where they do their mambo act.
别人代替她去不行吗？
Can't someone else fill in?
不，别人不行
No, "Miss Fix-it." Somebody else can't.
玛丽亚整天都得工作，她学不会的
Maria has to work all day. She can't learn the routines.
珍妮特得接替佩妮，每个人都得在这儿工作
And Janet has to fill in for Penny. Everybody works here.
你想去吗？从“赛门说”游戏里挤出时间来？
You wanna do it? Take time out from "Simon Says"?
这主意不错
It's not a bad idea.
我开玩笑的
It was a joke.
- 她会跳  - 这是我听过的最愚蠢的主意
- She can move.  - It's the dumbest idea I ever heard of.
- 我连梅伦格舞都不会跳  - 看见了吧？
- I can't even do the merengue.  - See?
你是个强大的舞伴，你能带任何人跳舞
You're a strong partner. You can lead anybody.
她连梅伦格舞都不会跳，她做不到的
She can't even do the merengue. She cannot do it.
- 不！ - 哦，对不起，对不起
- No!  - Oh, sorry. Sorry.
你别踩在一拍上
You don't step on the one.
你要从二拍开始，明白吗？
You gotta start on the two. Find the two. Understand?
- 我以前从没跳过这样的舞  - 是一、二、三、四
- I never did any of these dances before.  - It's one, two, three, four.
音乐开始后，到二的时候你才开始跳，明白吗？
When the music starts, you don't dance until the two. Got it?
放松，放松
Relax, relax.
深呼吸
Breathe.
姿势
Frame.
不
Nope.
再来
Again.
噢
Ow.
二、三、四，二、三、四
Two, three, four. Two, three, four.
不要向后靠，挺起胸来
Don't lean back. Lifting up.
二、三、四，肩膀向下压
Two, three, four. Shoulders down.
再来，集中注意力，还有…
Again. Concentrate. And...
脚跟不要着地
Don't put your heel down.
- 脚跟不要着地  - 我没有…
- Don't put your heel down.  - I didn't...
脚尖着地，听我的
Stay on the toe. Just listen to me.
这些步子还不够
The steps aren't enough.
感受音乐
Feel the music.
不在一拍，这不是曼波
It's not on the one. It's not the mambo.
这是一种感觉，一种心跳
It's a feeling, a heartbeat.
不要那么用力
Don't try so hard.
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
二、三、四，二、三、四
Two, three, four. Two, three, four.
深呼吸
Breathe.
抬头，保持姿势，保持
Head up. Lock your frame. Lock it.
看，面条胳膊
Look, spaghetti arm.
这是我的跳舞空间，这是你的跳舞空间
This is my dance space. This is your dance space.
井水不犯河水，你要保持姿势
I don't go into yours. You don't go into mine. You gotta hold the frame.
再来
Again.
姿势
Frame.
后退，放松
Back. Easy.
旋转，旋转，上，下，你以后会学这个的
And turn, turn. Down. And lift. You'll learn that later.
来吧
And come on.
向下，扭转
Down. Twist.
弯腰
And the bow.
- 对不起，对不起  - 你想杀了我吗？
- Sorry. Sorry.  - You trying to kill me?
你得集中注意力！你觉得很好玩吗？
You gotta concentrate! Is that your idea of fun?
事实上是的
As a matter of fact it is.
我们还有两天就要上场了，你却还不教我跳跃，我还没学会旋转
We do the show in two days, you won't show me lifts, I'm not sure of turns.
我做这些都是为了救你们，我真想把你摔到地上
I'm doing all this to save your ass, but I'd rather drop you on it!
我们出去吧
Let's get out of here.
该死！
Shit!
我把钥匙锁在车里了！
I locked the keys in the car!
你淋湿了，对吧？
You're getting wet, right?
- 你真疯狂  - 什么？
- You're wild.  - What?
你真疯狂！
You're wild!
现在，跳跃中需要记住最重要的事情是平衡
Now, the most important thing to remember in lifts is balance.
哇！哇！
Whoa! Whoa!
我现在做到了
I got it now.
你在哪儿学的跳舞？
So where'd you learn to be a dancer?
一天一个人走进一家小餐馆…
Well, this guy came into this luncheonette one day and...
我们都在那儿坐着无所事事
we were all sitting around doing nothing.
他说亚曼瑞在招老师
And he said that Arthur Murray was giving a test for instructors.
如果你通过了…
So, if you passed...
他们会教你跳不同的舞，教你怎么分解动作再教给别人
they teach you different dances, show you how to break them down, teach them.
什么？
What?
很好
Good.
不要往下看，看这里，很好
Don't look down. Look here. Good.
然后…
And...
现在膝盖弯曲，然后往上跳，跳，跳
Now, bend your knees and go up. Go, go.
不错，现在如果你不信任我，你就会伤到我
Good try. Now, you'll hurt me if you don't trust me, all right?
现在，跳，跳，跳
Now, go, go. Go.
很好，现在跳吧
Good. Now, I'm gonna go up.
知道吗，练习跳跃最好的地方是水中
You know, the best place to practice lifts is in the water.
弯下膝盖，然后…跳
Just bend your knees. And... go.
很好
Good.
很好，很好
Good. Good.
保持这个姿势，保持住
Now hold the position. Hold it.
很好，别动！别动！
Good. Don't break! Don't break!
再来一次
Let's do it again.
好，一、二、三
All right. One, two, three.
哦，对不起
Oh, sorry.
很好，保持…不
Good. Keep... No, don't.
还不错
It's not too bad.
- 再来一次  - 好，在我的头上，跳
- One more time.  - Okay. Over my head. Go.
我不敢相信就是今晚
I can't believe it's tonight.
还有二十分钟开始，我们去车上换衣服
Sheldrake's 20 minutes away. We'll change in the car.
舒马赫太太，等等，我们来帮你
Mrs. Schumacher. Hey, wait, we'll help you.
这么多垃圾，这么多垃圾
Such junk. Such junk.
我上过贝尼・伯恩斯坦舞蹈学校
Benny Bernstein's Dancing School, that's where I went.
乔治・伯恩斯曾是一名老师
George Burns was a teacher.
- 谢谢  - 不用谢
- Thank you.  - You're welcome.
我只要压低我的肩，抬高我的头…
I'll just keep my shoulders down, my head up...
保持姿势，踮着脚尖…
my frame locked, stay on my toes...
如果我忘了这些步子怎么办？
What if I forget the steps?
挺胸，留心姿势，记住让他来引导你
Pull up, watch the frame. And remember, let him lead you.
我害怕我会什么都忘了，头昏眼花脸着地
I'm afraid I'm gonna forget to spike, get dizzy and fall on my face.
不，不要看我的脚，抬头睁眼…
No. Don't look at my feet, keep my head up, my eyes open...
拉紧胳膊，保持姿势，挺胸…
tension in my arms, my frame locked, seat pulled up...
谢谢，宝贝
Thanks, Baby.
我只是想让你知道我不跟人随便上床…
I just want you to know that I don't sleep around...
不管罗比跟你说了什么
whatever Robbie might have told you.
我以为他爱我
And I thought that he loved me.
我当真了
I thought it was something special.
不管怎样，我只是想然你知道
Anyway, I just wanted you to know that.
我看起来怎么样？
So, how does it look?
我很害怕
I'm scared.
我很害怕，宝贝
I'm so scared, Baby.
别担心
Don't worry.
你会好起来的
You'll be fine.
宾果！宾果！宾果！凯勒曼山庄的星期四之夜
Bingo! Bingo! Bingo! That's right. It's Thursday night at Kellerman's.
今晚是宾果之夜
That's bingo night.
- 嘿，待会儿跳支舞怎么样？ - 也许吧，谁知道呢？
- Hey, how about a dance later?  - Could be. Who knows?
- 丽萨，你得帮我个忙  - 我不帮
- Lisa, you have to do something for me.  - I don't have to.
就告诉爸妈我头疼休息，好吗？
Just tell Mom and Dad I have a headache and I'm in bed, okay?
再见
Bye.
秋沙鸭酒店隆重推出约翰尼・卡斯尔和他的舞伴…
The Sheldrake Hotel is proud to present Johnny Castle and partner...
表演的“曼波魔力”
in "Mambo Magic."
放松
Relax.
现在跟着我的舞步走
Now spot a lead.
走错了！
Wrong way!
这边
Over here.
准备好跳了吗？
Ready for the lift?
来吧
Come on.
继续，继续
Keep going. Keep going.
…因为无论你现在身处何方，我想让你望着天空
...because wherever you are now, I want you to look at the sky.
看着那些星星，下面是漂流者乐队
Look at those stars. What a show. Here are The Drifters.
做得不错，你很努力
You did good. You worked hard.
我看见凯勒曼的一对老夫妇，我就想，完了
I saw that old couple from Kellerman's and I thought that was it.
我也是，我也是
Me too. Me too.
知道吗，第二个旋转你真的找到感觉了
You know, by the second turn you really had it.
- 但我没做跳跃的动作  - 你做得不错
- But I didn't do the lift.  - You did real good.
谢谢
Thanks.
约翰尼！
Johnny!
快来，佩妮出事了
Come on. It's Penny.
- 她在等你回来  - 你叫救护车了吗？
- She wouldn't go until you returned.  - Did you call an ambulance?
她说医院会叫警察的，她要我答应
She said the hospital would call the police. She made me promise.
他连麻醉剂都没有用，什么都没用
He didn't use no ether, nothing.
- 你不是说他是个真正的医学博士吗？ - 他只有一把没有消过毒的刀和桌子
- I thought you said he was a real M.D.?  - He had a dirty knife and a table.
我在走廊里就能听见她的尖叫
I could hear her screaming in the hallway.
我发誓，我试着进去
I swear to God, I tried to get in.
没事的，约翰尼在这里
It's all right. Johnny's here.
什么？怎么了，宝贝？
What? What is it, Baby?
- 是丽萨吗？ - 不是
- Is it Lisa?  - No.
对不起，对不起！大家都请出去
Excuse me. Excuse me! Everybody clear out, please.
是的，我知道很疼，我们会解决的
Yes, I know that hurts. We're gonna take care of that.
- 谁对这个女孩负责？ - 我
- Who's responsible for this girl?  - I am.
求求你，她…
Please, is she...
医生，太谢谢你了
Doc, thanks a lot.
我不知道如何感谢你
I don't know how to thank you.
- 我的钱就用在这儿了？ - 对不起，我没想撒谎的
- Was that what my money paid for?  - I'm sorry. I never meant to lie.
你不是我以为的那个人，我快不认识你了
You're not the person I thought you were. I'm not sure who you are.
我不想你再跟那些人扯上关系了
I don't want you to have anything to do with those people.
你别再和那些人来往了！
Nothing! You're to have nothing to do with them ever again!
我不会告诉你妈的，现在我去睡觉了
I won't tell your mother about this. Right now I'm going to bed.
在你妈看见你之前把你脸上的东西清理掉
And take that stuff off your face before your mother sees you!
没事吧，杰克？
Is everything all right, Jake?
没事，玛姬，回去睡觉吧
It's all right, Marge. Go back to sleep.
我可以进来吗？
Can I come in?
我想这个房间实在不怎么样，你也许有个很好的房间
I got a... I guess it's not a great room. You probably got a great room.
不，这房间不错！
No. It's a great room!
不要关
Leave it on.
我为我父亲对你态度道歉
I'm sorry about the way my father treated you.
不，你父亲很好
No. Your father was great.
他很好，他医好了佩妮
He was great. The way he took care of Penny.
我是说他对你的态度
I mean the way he was with you.
其实他针对的是我
It's really me it has to do with.
约翰尼我来这儿是因为我的父亲…
Johnny, I came here because my father...
不，他救了佩妮…这我永远也做不到
No. The way he saved her... I could never do anything like that.
这很了不起，人们不把我当回事是因为我的确什么都不是
That was something. People treat me like I'm nothing because I am nothing.
不是这样的！你是一切！
That's not true! You're everything!
你不明白像我这种人的感受
You don't understand the way it is for somebody like me.
上个月我吃糖充饥
Last month I'm eating candy to stay alive.
这个月女人们却往我的口袋里塞钻石
This month, women are stuffing diamonds in my pockets.
我站在屎的上方保持平衡而我可能再次摔到屎堆里
I'm balancing on shit and I can be down there again.
不，不是这样的！你不必这样的！
No, it's not the way it is! It doesn't have to be that way!
我从没见过像你这样的人，你觉得你能改变世界
I've never known anyone like you. You think you can make the world better.
有人不见了，你找到他们；有人留血了…
Somebody's lost, you find them. Somebody's bleeding...
我去找我爸爸，真的很勇敢，就像你说的
I go get my daddy. That's really brave, like you said.
这需要多大的胆子才敢去找他呀！
That took a lot of guts to go to him!
你什么都不怕
You are not scared of anything.
我什么都怕！我怕我看见的一切
I'm scared of everything! I'm scared of what I saw.
我怕我所做的一切，我怕我自己
I'm scared of what I did, who I am.
我害怕走出这个房间后这辈子再也感受不到…
I'm scared of walking out of here and never feeling for the rest of my life...
和你在一起的那种感觉！
the way I feel when I'm with you!
和我跳支舞吧
Dance with me.
什么，这儿？
What, here?
这儿
Here.
歌手、舞者、演员们，今天是你们的幸运日！
Singers, dancers, actors, this is your lucky day!
年度凯勒曼季末才艺表演的试镜…
Auditions for the annual Kellerman end-of-the-season talent show...
在表演厅里开始
beginning in the playhouse.
- 大家都去参加表演吗？ - 我们明天就走
- So everyone gonna be in the show?  - We're leaving tomorrow.
以避开周末塞车
Miss the weekend traffic.
但是我们付了一直到周日的钱
But we're paid up 'til Sunday.
- 不参加表演了吗？ - 我说了明天就走
- And miss the show?  - I said we're leaving tomorrow.
- 我要在表演里唱歌  - 这可是个盛大的活动
- I was going to sing in the show.  - It's the big event.
人们带来了他们的绝活，你不想错过的
People bring their own arrangements. You don't want to miss it.
宝贝，我需要你做道具
Baby, I need you for props.
你为什么想提前离开？
Why would you want to leave early?
我只是想想，你想的话我们就留下来吧
It was just an idea. We can stay if you want to.
- 那么你打算唱什么？ - 《I Feel Pretty》
- So, what were you planning to sing?  - "I Feel Pretty."
或者《What Do the Simple Folk Do？》
Or "What Do the Simple Folk Do?"
或者《I Feel Pretty》，你觉得怎么样，爸爸？
Or "I Feel Pretty." What do you think, Daddy?
你看起来好多了
You look much better.
你父亲刚刚来过，他是个很好的人
You just missed your father. He's such a wonderful man.
对不起，我没意识到…
I'm sorry. I didn't realize...
你不可能意识到的，没关系
You couldn't have. It's okay.
- 你怎么样？ - 我很好
- So, how you doin'?  - I'm okay.
豪斯曼医生说我会好的
Dr. Houseman says I'm going to be fine.
- 我还能生孩子  - 哦，佩妮，真棒
- I can still have children.  - Oh, Penny, that's really great.
昨晚怎么样？
So, how did it go last night?
很好
Good.
很好，我没做跳跃动作，但还好
Fine. I didn't do the lifts, but it was good.
好了，我想我该走了
Well, I guess I gonna go.
再见
See ya.
- 他说你会好的是吗？ - 你在做什么？
- So, he says you're going to be fine?  - What are you doing?
- 我会告诉马克思你的奶奶去世了  - 我告诉过你多少次…
- I'll tell Max your grandmother died.  - How many times have you told me...
不要和他们纠缠不清？
never get mixed-up with them?
我知道我在做什么
I know what I'm doing.
你听我说，你现在就得停止
You listen to me. You've got to stop it now.
我得赶紧走了，我得去教克莱默夫妇跳舞
Look, I gotta run. I got a lesson with the Kramers.
如果我不在那儿，他们会杀了对方的
They'll kill each other if I'm not there.
好吧，当然，你得走了
Well, sure. You've gotta go.
再见
I'll see ya.
现在是雨天游戏时间，给客人们别上尾巴
It's rainy day game time. Pin the tail on the guest.
赢取十盒克里内克丝面巾纸或者一头公山羊！
Win ten boxes of Kleenex or a billy goat!
天哪，我烦死这场雨了
God, I am so sick of this rain.
这提醒我不要去尼亚加拉大瀑布度蜜月
Remind me not to take my honeymoon at Niagara Falls.
那你就去阿卡普尔科吧
So, you go to Acapulco. It'll be fine.
我的米黄色闪光唇膏呢？
Where is my beige iridescent lipstick?
我知道我把它放在抽屉里了
I know I put it in this drawer.
宝贝，这种天气你要去哪儿？
Baby, where are you going in this weather?
呃，西厅有看手势猜字谜游戏
Uh, they're having charades in the west lobby.
真是个社团活跃分子
Quite the little joiner, aren't we?
- 你有过很多女人吗？ - 什么？
- Have you had many women?  - What?
宝贝，说吧
Baby, come on.
告诉我，我想知道
Tell me. I want to know.
你得明白这是怎么一回事
You gotta understand what it's like.
你从街上走来然后突然出现在这里
You come from the streets and suddenly you're up here.
女人们投怀送抱，散发着香味
Women are throwing themselves at you and they smell so good.
她们自己照顾自己
They really take care of themselves.
我从来不知道女人可以那样
I never knew women could be like that.
她们那么有钱，你觉得她们什么都了解
They're so goddamn rich you think they must know about everything.
她们往我手里塞她们房间的钥匙，一天两三次…
They're slippin' their room keys in my hand two and three times a day...
不同的女人…我觉得我很走运
different women... so, I think I'm scorin' big, right?
你觉得要是她们不在乎我，就不会做这些事，对吗？
You think, "They wouldn't be doing this if they didn't care about me, right?"
没关系，我明白，你只是在利用她们
That's all right. I understand. You were just using them, that's all.
不，不是这样的
No, that's not it.
问题是并非如此
That's the thing. It wasn't like that.
她们在利用我
They were using me.
你真正的名字是什么，宝贝？
What's your real name, Baby?
弗朗西丝，与美国内阁第一位女性成员同名
Frances, for the first woman in the Cabinet.
弗朗西丝，真是个成熟的名字
Frances. That's a real grownup name.
我决定跟罗宾做爱了
I've decided to go all the way with Robbie.
不，别跟像他那样的人
No, not with someone like him.
你觉得我们十周年的时候回来会是免费的吗？
Do you think if we came back for a ten-year anniversary, it would be free?
这样是不对的，你应该…
It's just wrong this way. It should be with someone...
和你喜欢的人才对
With someone that you sort of love.
算了吧，你一点也不在乎我
Come on. You don't care about me.
即使我和整个军队的人上床你也无所谓…
You wouldn't care if I humped the entire army...
只要我们在胡志明小道的右方
as long as we were on the right side of the Ho Chi Minh Trail.
你在乎的是你不再是爸爸的小女孩了
What you care about is that you're not Daddy's girl anymore.
他现在听我说话
He listens when I talk now.
你嫉妒
You hate that.
二、三，恰、恰、恰！
Two, three, cha-cha-cha.
我的姿势，我优美的弧线在哪儿呢？
My frame. Where's my pleasing arc?
面条胳膊！你能让我拉紧一点吗？
Spaghetti arms! Would you give me some tension, please?
你在侵占我的跳舞空间，这是我的跳舞空间
You're invading my dance space. This is my dance space.
那才是你的，我们恰恰
That's yours. Let's cha-cha.
不要往下看，看这里
Don't look down. Look right here.
- 你怎么叫你心爱的男孩？ - 到这儿来，心爱的男孩
- How you call your lover boy?  - Come here, lover boy.
- 如果他不回答呢？ - 哦，心爱的男孩
- And if he doesn't answer?  - Oh, lover boy.
- 如果他还不回答呢？ - 我就说…
- And if still doesn't answer?  - I simply say...
宝贝
Baby
哦，宝贝
O-Oh, baby
我亲爱的宝贝
My sweet baby
你是我的
You're the one
在上舞蹈课吗？
Takin' dance lessons?
我可以教你，孩子
I could teach ya, kid.
我爷爷让我负责最后的表演
My grandfather put me in charge of the final show.
我想跟你谈谈最后的舞蹈
I want to talk to you about the last dance.
我想来点刺激的
I'd like to shake things up a bit.
你知道，与时俱进的
You know, move with the times.
我有很多想法
I've got a lot of ideas.
我和员工们一直在努力…
I've been working with the staff kids...
将古巴韵律和灵魂舞蹈融合在一起
on a cross between a Cuban rhythm and soul dancing.
喂，伙计
Whoa, boy.
你没理解我的意思
Way over your head here.
你们总是跳曼波，是吧？
You always do the mambo, huh?
今年最后的舞蹈为什么不跳…
Why not dance this year's final dance...
泼格舞？
to the pachenga?
好
Right.
好吧，如果你想的话你也可以跳跟去年一样的…
Well, you're free to do the same, tired number as last year if you want...
但是明年我们会找一个新的舞者…
but next year we'll find another dance person...
- 他会欣然接受的…  - 好吧，尼尔，没问题
- who'll only be too happy...  - Sure, Neil. No problem.
季末我们会跳泼格舞的
We'll end the season with the pachenga.
不错
Great idea.
有时候很难与他谈话，但女士们似乎很喜欢他
Sometimes he's hard to talk to, but the ladies seem to like him.
一定要让他给你上足半小时的课，你付了钱的
See that he gives you the full half-hour you're paying him for, kid.
那小子根本不懂舞蹈的创新
That little wimp. He wouldn't know a new idea if it hit him in the pachenga.
我可以告诉他一些新想法的
I could have told him some new ideas.
你怎么能让他那样和你说话？
Why did you let him talk to you that way?
- 什么，难道跟老板斗嘴吗？ - 你就告诉他你的想法
- What, fight the boss man?  - You tell him your ideas.
- 他也和别人一样  - 瞧，我了解这种人
- He's a person like everyone else.  - Look, I know these people.
富有而刻薄，他们不会听我的
They are rich and they're mean. They won't listen to me.
为什么不更努力地争取呢？让他们听见你的声音
Why not fight harder? Make them listen.
因为我需要这份该死的工作一直持续到明年夏天
Because I need this goddamned job lined up for next summer.
我爸爸今天打电话给我
My dad calls me today.
“好消息，”他说，“保罗叔叔，终于帮你在工会找了份差事”
"Good news," he says. "Uncle Paul can finally get you in the union."
什么工会？
What union?
家庭油漆工与水泥工，一七九号为您服务
The House Painters and Plasterers Local Number 179 at your service.
我一直在思考骨牌理论
I've been thinking a lot about the Domino Theory.
现在如果越南失败了，中国是下一个吗？
Now, when Viet Nam falls, is China Next?
他们应该没看见我们
I don't think they saw us.
更努力地争取，是吗？
Fight harder, huh?
我没看见你努力争取，告诉你爸爸我是你的男人
I don't see you fightin' so hard, tellin' Daddy I'm your guy.
我会的，我爸爸的情况比较复杂
I will. With my father, it's complicated.
- 我会告诉他的  - 我不相信你，宝贝
- I will tell him.  - I don't believe you, Baby.
我觉得…
I don't think...
你并没有告诉他的打算
that you ever had any intention of telling him.
从来没有
Ever.
好了，朋友们，快结束了，劳动节的周末到了
Well, Cousin, it's almost over. Labor Day weekend is here.
很快就要回到书本和工作中了，真可怕！
Soon it's back to the old books and back to work. What a terrible thought!
你看见约翰尼了吗？
Have you seen Johnny?
对不起
I'm sorry.
看来我在两姐妹中选错了人
Looks like I picked the wrong sister.
没关系，宝贝，我也去过贫民窟
That's okay, Baby. I went slummin' too.
打我啊
Hit me.
从这儿滚出去，你不配
Get out of here. You're not worth it.
大赢一笔，莫尔
Win big, Moe.
像往常一样
As always.
这是我们在一起的最后一夜了，亲爱的，我为我们做了点安排
This is our last night together, lover. I've got something worked out for us.
对不起，先生，下一个是海盗号码
Excuse me, sir. The pirate number's next.
哦，谢谢，嘿，孩子
Oh, thanks. Hey, kid.
我整个周末都在玩牌，今天还得玩一整晚
I've been playing cards all weekend and I've got an all-night game tonight.
你为什么不给我妻子多上点舞蹈课呢？
Why don't you give my wife some extra dance lessons?
对不起，普莱斯曼先生…
I'm sorry, Mr. Pressman...
我整个周末都得忙着排练节目
but I'm booked up for the whole weekend with the show.
没有时间做别的
I won't have time for anything else.
我想我不该收下这些钱
I don't think it'd be fair to take the money.
我决定今晚就和罗比在一起
I've decided tonight's the night with Robbie.
他还不知道呢
He doesn't even know yet.
是我
It's me.
妈的！
Holy shit!
你想听些疯狂的事情吗？
You wanna hear somethin' crazy?
昨晚我…
Last night I...
我梦见我们一起散步，遇见了你爸爸
I dreamt we were walking along and we met your father.
他说，“来吧，”然后用胳膊揽着我
He said, "Come on," and he put his arm around me.
就像对罗比那样
Just like he did with Robbie.
当你看见一个病人觉得他没事，可你一看X光片…
You know how you feel when you see a patient and you think he's all right...
却发现和你想的完全不同，你会有什么感觉？
then you look at the X rays and it's nothing like you thought?
发生什么事了？
What happened?
这就好像你发现你的员工竟是一个小偷
It's exactly what it's like when you find out one of your staff's a thief.
莫尔・普莱斯曼昨晚玩牌的时候钱包被偷了
Moe Pressman's wallet was stolen when he was playing pinochle last night.
钱包放在挂在椅背上的外套里
It was in his jacket hanging on the back of his chair.
他一点半放在那里，四点时他又看了一下…
He had it at 1:30 and when he checked again at quarter of 4:00...
钱包却不见了
it was missing.
薇薇安说她记得那个跳舞的小子，约翰尼…
Vivian thinks she remembers this dance kid Johnny...
从旁边路过
walking by.
我们就问他，“你有昨晚不在场的证据吗？”
So we ask him, "You have an alibi for last night?"
他说他在房间里独自看书
He says he was alone in his room reading.
约翰尼房里根本没有书！
There are no books in Johnny's room!
一定有什么误会，我知道不是约翰尼干的
There's been a mistake. I know Johnny didn't do it.
秋沙鸭酒店也有类似的小偷，这儿以前也发生过
There's been similar thefts at the Sheldrake. It's happened here before.
- 三个钱包  - 我知道不是他干的
- Three other wallets.  - I know he didn't do it.
别管这事，宝贝
Stay out of it, Baby.
等等，别把那些桌子放在一起
Wait. Don't put those tables together. Come on.
爸爸，我需要你的帮助，我知道约翰尼没有偷莫尔的钱包
Daddy, I need your help. I know Johnny didn't take Moe's wallet.
- 哦？你怎么知道？ - 我不能告诉你
- Oh? How do you know?  - I can't tell you.
- 请相信我，爸爸  - 对不起，宝贝，我不能
- Just please trust me, Daddy.  - I'm sorry, Baby. I can't.
这块丹麦蛋糕富含蛋白质
This Danish is pure protein.
也许不是约翰尼干的，谁都可能偷了钱包
Maybe Johnny didn't do it. Anyone could've taken it.
也许是…
Maybe it was, uh...
也许是那对个子小小的老夫妇，舒马赫夫妇
It could've been that little, old couple, the Schumachers.
- 我看到她拿着几个钱包  - 西尔维娅和西德尼？
- I saw her with a couple of wallets.  - Sylvia and Sidney?
宝贝，你不能随便冤枉无辜的人
Baby, you don't go around accusing innocent people.
我还在秋沙鸭酒店看见他们了，你说那儿也有人被偷
I even saw them at the Sheldrake. You said something was stolen from there.
我有目击证人，而那个小子没有不在场证据
I got an eyewitness and the kid has no alibi.
来吧，尼尔，你来学学如何解雇你的员工
Come on, Neil. You'll learn what it's like to fire an employee.
等一下，我知道约翰尼没偷钱包
Wait a minute. I know Johnny didn't take the wallet.
我知道，因为他昨晚一直在他房间里
I know because he was in his room all night.
我知道是因为我当时和他在一起
And the reason I know is because I was with him.
我跟你说过我说的是实话
I told you I was telling the truth.
对不起，我对你撒了谎
I'm sorry I lied to you.
但你也撒了谎
But you lied too.
你告诉我每个人都是一样的，都理应受到公平的对待
You told me everyone was alike and deserved a fair break.
但你指的是像你一样的人
But you meant everyone who is like you.
你告诉我你想要我改变世界，让它更美好
You told me you wanted me to change the world, to make it better.
但你指的是成为一名律师或者经济学家…
But you meant by becoming a lawyer or an economist...
嫁给一个哈佛毕业生
and marrying someone from Harvard.
我并不为自己感到骄傲
I'm not proud of myself.
但我也是这个家庭的一员，你不能一直用沉默对待我
But I'm in this family too. You can't keep giving me the silent treatment.
我有很多事情都不是你想像的那样
There are a lot of things about me that aren't what you thought.
但如果你爱我，你就得爱我的一切
But if you love me, you have to love all the things about me.
而我爱你
And I love you.
对不起，我让你失望了，真对不起，爸爸
I'm sorry I let you down. I'm so sorry, Daddy.
但你也让我失望了
But you let me down too.
我找你都找遍了
I have been lookin' for you all over.
他们找到了舒马赫夫妇
They found the Schumachers.
从他们的水杯上取了指纹
Fingerprinted their water glasses.
发现他们在亚利桑那和佛罗里达都被通缉…
Found out they were wanted in Arizona and in Florida...
今年夏天他们在这儿大捞了一笔
and they made a fortune here this summer.
那么一切都没事了
So then it's all right.
我就知道会解决的
I knew it would work out.
- 我就知道他们得道歉  - 我被解雇了，宝贝
- I knew they'd have to apologize.  - I'm out, Baby.
他们还是解雇了你，因为我
They fired you anyway because of me.
如果我悄悄走人，我还能拿到夏季的奖金
And if I leave quietly, I'll get my summer bonus.
那么我做的一切都是徒劳
So I did it for nothing.
我伤害了家人，你失去了工作…一切都白做了！
I hurt my family, you lost your job anyway... I did it for nothing!
不，没有白做
No, not for nothing.
以前从来没有人为我做过这些
Nobody has ever done anything like that for me before.
你说得对，不管做什么你都赢不了
You were right. You can't win no matter what you do.
听我说，我不想从你口中听到这句话，你可以的
Listen to me. I don't want to hear that from you. You can.
我曾经这么以为
I used to think so.
豪斯曼医生，我能不能…
Dr. Houseman, can I, uh...
瞧，我就快走了，我知道你现在想什么
Look, I'm going anyway and I know what you must be thinking.
你根本不了解我
You don't know anything at all about me.
我知道你想让宝贝和你一样
I know you want Baby to be like you.
众人景仰的那种人
The kind of person people look up to.
宝贝就像那样，如果你能知道…
Baby is like that. If you could just see...
不用你来告诉我该知道什么
Don't you tell me what to see.
我知道我眼前的这个人让他的舞伴陷入麻烦…
I see someone in front of me who got his partner in trouble...
还把她送到屠夫手中…
and sent her off to some butcher...
同时还追求一个天真的少女，就像我的女儿
while he moved on to an innocent, young girl like my daughter.
好吧，我想那就是你看到的
Yeah, I guess that's what you would see.
没有你在这儿哪怕只呆一天我都无法想像
I can't imagine being here without you even one day.
就想想你会有更多的时间练习马术和槌球
Just think, you have more time for horseshoes and croquet.
也许现在他们会把你锯成七块
Maybe they'll saw you in seven pieces now.
我想我们让每个人都大吃了一惊
I guess we surprised everybody.
我想是的
I guess we did.
不会再有遗憾了
Hardly would be sorry.
我也不会
Neither will I.
再见
I'll see ya.
我来帮你做头发
I'll do your hair.
你会很漂亮的，如果…
It could look pretty if...
你还是这样更漂亮
You're prettier your way.
就这样
This way.
凯勒曼的朋友们，我们相聚齐声唱
Kellermans, we come together Singing all as one
又一季才艺展示，我们共享乐趣多
We have shared another season's Talent, play and fun
夏日即将要结束，秋日即将要开始
Summer days will soon be over Soon the autumn starts
今夜回忆又唤起，翩翩浮现于心中
And tonight the memories whisper Softly in our hearts
手拉手啊心连心，欢声笑语多欢畅
Join hands and hearts and voices Voices, hearts and hands
在这凯勒曼山庄，友谊如青山常在
At Kellerman's the friendships Last long as the mountain stands
时时刻刻日与夜，无论天气雨或晴
Daytime, nighttime, any hour Weather rain or shine
游戏讲座与玩笑，音乐声中乐融融
Games and lectures, jokes and music Happily combine
祝你在医学院好运，孩子
Good luck in medical school, son.
我想谢谢你帮我摆脱了佩妮的麻烦
And I wanted to thank you for your help with the Penny situation.
- 我想我们都她被搞得一团糟  - 什么？
- I guess we've all gotten into messes.  - What?
我以为宝贝已经告诉你了，我也不确定
I thought Baby told you. Look, I'm not sure.
佩妮说的，不过你也知道像那样的女人可以勾搭…
Penny said so, but you know with girls like that. They're liable to pin it...
周围任何一个男人
on any guy around.
- 今天有什么最新消息吗？ - 结束了
- What's the hot tip for the day?  - Finished.
你和我，蒂托，我们全都看见了
You and me, Tito. We've seen it all, eh?
波巴和泽达给住宿生送上第一杯经过巴氏消毒的牛奶
Bubbah and Zeda serving the first pasteurized milk to the boarders.
战争岁月里我们没有肉吃
Through the war years when we didn't have any meat.
大萧条时期我们什么也没有
Through the Depression when we didn't have anything.
许许多多的变化，马克思
Lots of changes, though, Max.
可这一次不是什么巨大的变化
It's not the changes so much this time.
而是一切好像都要结束了
It's that it all seems to be ending.
你以为孩子们还想和他们的父母来跳狐步舞吗？
You think kids want to come with their parents and take fox-trot lessons?
去欧洲旅行才是孩子们想要的
Trips to Europe, that's what the kids want.
三天游历二十二个国家
Twenty-two countries in three days.
感觉好像一切都在渐行渐远
It feels like it's all slipping away.
感受假期的心跳，烦恼再也看不到
But the heartbeats of vacation There no cares are seen
游客员工与来宾，加入最后大合唱
So let's join in just one last chorus Visitors, staff and guests
莫忘共享的岁月，老友才是最好的
What we've shared won't be forgotten Old friends are the best
没人会把宝贝放在角落里
Nobody puts Baby in the corner.
来吧
Come on.
很抱歉打断大家…
Sorry about the disruption, folks...
季末最后一支舞总是由我来跳的
but I always do the last dance of the season.
今年有人让我别跳了
This year somebody told me not to.
所以我要来跳自己的舞，和一位出色的舞伴…
So I'm gonna do my kind of dancin' with a great partner...
她不仅是一位出色的舞者…
who's not only a terrific dancer...
而且她让我知道有人…
but somebody who's taught me that there are people...
愿意为别人站出来，不管代价是什么
willing to stand up for other people no matter what it costs them.
她让我知道…
Somebody who's taught me...
我想做一个什么样的人
about the kind of person I want to be.
弗朗西丝・豪斯曼小姐
Miss Frances Houseman.
坐下，杰克
Sit down, Jake.
我想她是遗传我的天赋
I think she gets this from me.
你有这曲子的乐谱吗？
Do you have sheet music on this stuff?
我知道你不是让佩妮怀孕的人
I know you weren't the one who got Penny in trouble.
当我错了，我就会说我错了
When I'm wrong, I say I'm wrong.
你刚才在那儿看起来棒极了
You looked wonderful out there.